budgetair.ie 2014-05-28

# Privacy Statement | BudgetAir.ie

## Privacy statement

### Privacy statement

### 1.1 General

Careful treatment of your personal data is very important both to you and budgetair.ie. All information you provide us with shall be treated with the greatest of care. Your personal details will only be used in the way described in this privacy statement.

### 1.2 Disclosure of personal details to third parties

budgetair.ie will not disclose any personal information to third parties, unless this is required for performing services or required by legal provisions. Our suppliers are increasingly required to provide various local authorities, such as the customs and immigration authorities with personal data and travel details of their customers. This is, for instance, required by airline companies and if you travel to or via the United States or Canada. Disclosure of this information is for your own safety. Although budgetair.ie is required to provide your personal details to the supplier, the necessity stated above is a responsibility and activity of the supplier. If you have any objection to this, you should report this prior to confirming your booking. budgetair.ie reserves the right to provide details to the competent authorities, in the event of fraud or misuse of means of payment, or in the event that a user intentionally causes damage through the use of our website.

### 1.3 Use of our website

Our website can be consulted anonymously. Only when you order products, book a trip, want to request the newsletter or wish to contact us by email form, we ask you to enter relevant personal details.

### 1.4 Profile

Our website can save your profile which is secured by a login name and password. A profile offers you extra convenience when making a booking. You should keep your login name and password confidential and not disclose these to third parties to prevent others from accessing your personal details.

### 1.5 Newsletter

If you wish to be regularly informed about our special offers or promotional activities, you can subscribe to our newsletter. You can do this by sending us your email address and possibly your name and gender via this site. Next, you will receive an email asking you to confirm that you agree to the use of your personal details for sending you the newsletter. If you no longer wish to receive the newsletter, you can cancel your newsletter subscription at any time.

### 1.6 What details do we collect?

In order to guarantee the correct execution of the trip you have booked, we ask you to enter both your personal details and the details of your travel companions. By disclosing the details of your travel companions, you confirm that you are authorised in your capacity as booking client to do so.

We may collect the following data:

  * your full name as per your passport, including gender, initials, full first name, middle name and surname;
  * your address, postcode, city, country. You may provide a different invoice or shipping address for travel documents;
  * your phone number, fax number, mobile phone number, phone number for the people at home in case of emergency just before or during your trip;
  * your email address;
  * additional personal health information insofar as provided voluntarily and necessary for correct proceeding of your trip;
  * additional personal preferences insofar as provided voluntarily and necessary for a correct proceeding of your trip;
  * customer account numbers of third parties (such as a frequent flyer number) or of suppliers, allowing you to qualify for privileges or other benefits attached to this;
  * your computer's IP address, to prevent misuse and fraud.

Any credit card or bank account details are not collected or stored by budgetair.ie. Payment transactions are processed via the secured site of Ogone Payment Services. See also under 1.9

### 1.7 Transfer of Information

If it is necessary to transfer your data to a company based outside the EU (eg. for the purpose of fulfilling your booking) then we will make every effort to ensure that your personal data is processed in accordance with this privacy policy and as permitted or required by law.

### 1.8 Visitor’s registration and ‘cookies’

This website uses so-called cookies in order to track our visitors’ internet behaviour. A cookie is an internet file saved on your computer by our website and stores your personal preferences set on our website. Cookies will help you look up the required information on our website or use your personal profile environment. Furthermore, we also use cookies to show you interesting personalized offers on other websites. Every internet user is free to reject these cookies by adjusting his browser settings. Note, however, that this might lead to your not being able to access some of our website’s pages.

### 1.9 Protection of personal details

To guarantee the privacy of your details on our website, there are different types of security we employ. The personal data you provide us with through our website when making or completing a booking, are secured by means of Secure Socket Layers (SSL). In addition, all our systems are protected by a firewall to prevent unauthorised access.

### 1.10 Payments

Credit card payments made through our website are processed by Ogone Payment Services. Ogone is one of the major processors of internet payments. Ogone uses the Secure Socket Layer security protocol. As part of this, your credit card details are transmitted in encrypted format to the credit card company. These data cannot be intercepted by third parties. The messages that Ogone sends to us are all encrypted as well. Your credit card details are stored in the very well protected computers of Ogone Payment Services. Moreover, your credit card details will not be disclosed to budgetair.ie.

### 1.11 Links to other websites

This website contains references to other websites. It is important to realise that you leave our website when you click on one of these links. We advise you to carefully read the privacy statements of these websites before sending any personal details to them. budgetair.ie is not responsible for the privacy policies of these websites.

### 1.12 Job application

It is possible to apply for a job via our website. You can either send an unsolicited application or respond to an announced vacancy. You are requested to provide your personal details. These details will solely be used by our HR department so they can contact you with respect to your application. You can decide yourself which personal details you wish to provide via our website. Please bear in mind that you should provide sufficient details for us to contact you.

### 1.13 Access to personal details

At all times you can request us to allow you access to your personal details. You can also request us to remove your personal details from our systems, insofar as allowed under statutory and fiscal regulations. Please contact the Customer Services department of budgetair.ie for both requests.

### 1.14 Features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers

  * Third party vendors, including Google, show our ads on sites on the internet.
  * We use analytics data to also inform and optimize our ad campaigns based on a user's prior visits to our website.
  * Users may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCjWbybrwQCexlfuuXO841JrFiWt-GPpirKfelo4L4oMleHCtN5PCUzr5eBQBvB96fEhvPzHBAS1IbP57C_I6ZPP-lOnkeKc5z7pu7Zploftf8Vb-vkwXcelil8yPs7O4By2C4I91fNU7QUupzJ4sHs87HFiEiP-izCDTSgy6jmf9RYy5_M&hl=en).  
In addition, users can also opt out of a third party vendor's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Users may opt out of our use of Google Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics Opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * We have reporting of users’ interactions with our ads and of users’ views of our ads across the Google Display Network or DoubleClick for Advertisers in conjunction with activity on our site.

### 1.15 Changes to our privacy policy

All changes in the way BudgetAir.ie collects, processes and uses your personal details, will be described in future versions of our Privacy Statement. You can always find the most recent Privacy Statement on our website.
